Guide to the Grace Cavalieri papers, 1945-2022 MS2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Published Works, 1969-2019; Series 4
  - Lummox #1, 2012; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Lummox, no. 4, 2015; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    Includes Cavalieri poems "Bluebirds", "Truly a Problem of Reference". Includes interview by Cavalieri of Philip Levine from "The Poet and the Poem."
  - Lyricism, 2009 (Box 86, Folder 26)
  - Lyrismos vol. 3 no. 1, 1969 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Legacies" and "Prayer"
  - Magellanic Clouds of Vietnam (Box 86, Folder 27)
  - Man Love, 01/2009 (Box 86, Folder 28)
  - Mipoesias, 09/2007 (Box 86, Folder 29)
    Contents
    Cavalieri's Staff Biography
  - Mipoesias, 12/2007 (Box 86, Folder 30)
    Mipoesias
    picture and biography of Cavalieri
  - Mipoesias, 05/2008 (Box 86, Folder 31)
    Contains recipes by Cavalieri
  - Mipoesias, 09/2008 (Box 86, Folder 32)
    mipoesias
    Includes Cavalieri interview with Barbara Quick
  - Mipoesias, 12/2008 (Box 86, Folder 33)
    Includes interview of Cavalieri about "Anna Nicole: Poems"
  - Mipoesias, 2012; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Montpelier: Plus 4, 1980-1984 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Upon Dreaming a Proposition That All Truth Is a Conversion from Negative to Positive"
  - The Monserrat Review, issue 3, 2000 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Good Golly, Miss Molly"
  - The Monserrat Review no. 6, 2002 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri review "Ego as Beak" a review of Career Moves: Olson, Creeley, Zukofsky, Berrigan, and the American Avant-Garde"
  - The Monserrat Review, 2007-2009 (Box 86, Folder 34)
  - "My Green Emerald Dress" Introduction, 02/2009 (Box 86, Folder 35)
  - The New England Review vol. 1 no. 5, 04/1970 --05/1970 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Serving Notice"
  - The New England Review no. 6, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "January"
  - New Laurel Review Anthology Vol. 24, 2009; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    This issue includes poems by Grace Cavalieri "The Blue Trumpet" for Ahmos Zu-Bolton and "For Ahmos"
  - Nocturne vol. 2 no. 2, 1975 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Four from 'Points in Space'" and "Replacing Ironing Drudgery with Pressing Pleasure"
  - The North American Mentor vol. 6 no. 1, 1968 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Hanging the Host"
  - Northeast Rising Sun vol. 3 nos. 12 and 13, 1978 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    This issue includes the review of Grace Cavalieri book Why I Cannot Take a Lover.
  - Ocho no. 5, undated (Box 78, Folder 11)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "La Cucaracha", "At Jan's Funeral", and "Swan Lake".
  - Ocho no. 6, undated (Box 78, Folder 12)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Spirit of the Law: The Letter of the Law"
  - Ocho no. 7, undated (Box 78, Folder 13)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Infidelity" and "The Red Porsche and the Model"
  - Ocho no. 8, undated (Box 78, Folder 14)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "More Than Likely"
  - Ocho no. 9, 05/2007 (Box 78, Folder 15)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Anna Nicole: A Fiction #1", "Anna Nicole: A Fiction #2" and "Anna Nicole: A Fiction #3"
  - Ocho no. 12, 09/2008 (Box 86, Folder 36)
    Ocho
    edited by Grace Cavalieri
  - Ocho no. 23, 2009; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    This issue was edited by Grace Cavalieri
  - Ocho no. 26, 10/2009; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    This is the Travel Issue. Grace Cavalieri has two poems in this issue. "Mozambique" and "Transportation"
  - Ocho no. 29, 2010; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    Grace Cavalieri has a series of poems in this issue under the title Points in Space. These poems include "Flower Covering," "Crooked Pond," "Pure Cold Abyss," "Wilderness Mound," and "Supreme Rushing"
  - Ocho no. 31, 2011 April 21; Series 4 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    Includes poem by Grace Cavalieri: "The Stalker"
  - Oranges & Sardines vol.1 iss.1, 2008 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    Oranges and Sardines
    Cavalieri interviews Mark DOty
  - Oranges & Sardines vol.1 iss.2, 2008 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Oranges & Sardines vol.1 iss.3, 2008 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Paterson Literary Review no. 28, 1999 (Box 78, Folder 16)
    This issue includes an interview by Grace Cavalieri of Ishmael Reed.
  - Paterson Literary Review no. 29, 2000 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Children"
  - Paterson Literary Review no. 32, 2003 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    This issue includes Chapter 3 Memory in Prose: Replacing Loss and Chapter 6 Memory in Prose: Angelo.
  - Paterson Literary Review no. 34, 2005 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Sisters of the Cloth"
  - Paterson Literary review no. 39, 2011-2012; Series 4 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    By Grace Cavalieri: article on Diane de Prima, "on Loba: Revisited"
  - Paterson Literary Review no. 40, 2012; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Paterson: The Poets' City: An Anthology Celebrating the 25th Anniversary of the Poetry Center at Passaic County Community College, 2005 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "A Poet in the Schools. Paterson, New Jersey"
  - Paterson Literary Review no. 35, 2006 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri essay "Divorce Before Marriage: A Memory of Allen Ginsberg"
  - Paterson Literary Review 35, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Paterson Literary Review no. 37, 2009 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    Paterson no.37
    Includes poems by Cavalieri, "What I won" and "Tomato Pies 25 cents"
  - Paterson Literary Review: Enter with Applause, 2008 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Paterson Literary Review issue 46 Interview with Tracy K. Smith, 2018; Series 4 (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - Pembroke Magazine no. 34, 2002 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri play "Pinecrest Rest Haven" and a Grace Cavalieri interview with Stanley Kunitz.
  - Pembroke Magazine no. 36, 2004 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri book chapter "The Quality of Shame" from the book Memoirs
  - Pembroke Magazine no. 37, 2005 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Africa" "Ars Poetica" "Pretending to be a Widow" and "Spool of Love"
  - Pembroke Magazine no. 38, 2006 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    This issue includes: The Poet and the Poem from the Library of Congress interview by Grace Cavalieri with Stanley Plumly.
  - Pembroke Magazine: African American Feature no.39, undated (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Pembroke Magazine no. 40, 2008 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    Includes Cavalieri interview with Ted Kooser
  - Pembroke Magazine no. 41, 2009; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    This issue includes Grace Cavalieri's interivew with Donald Hall, 14th Poet Laureat of the United States.
  - Perpetuum Mobile vol. 3 issue 2, 10/2006 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "At the Funeral"
  - Perspectives: A Literary Occasional, 1974 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Fighting Off the Rescue Team"
  - Pioneering Italian American Culture, 2013; Series 4 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    Contains transcipt from Poets and the Poem interview with Daniella Gioseffi and review of Word Wounds and Water Flowers by Daniela Gioseffi
  - Poems Against War (The Liberation Issue) vol. 5, 08/2006 --11/2006 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Missing in Action" and "War Theater"
  - A Poet's Delight, 09/22/1993 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Poet Lore vol. 80 no. 2, 1985 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "It's Like Putting Cologne on a Pig"
  - Poet Lore vol. 81 no. 3, 1986 Fall; Series 4 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Poet Lore vol. 84 no. 4, 1989-1990 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Bluebiard of Happiness"
  - Poet Lore vol. 96 no. 2, 2001 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    This issue includes the review "Life and Death in Venice of the Carlo dell Corte's The Journey Ends Here: Notes for a Novel in Verse.
  - Poet Lore vol. 103 no.3/4, 2008 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    Poet Lore
    Includes essay by Cavalieri, "Poetry in the Air"
  - Poet Lore vol. 106 no. 1/2, 2011; Series 4 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    Includes: Lucille Clifton's last radio interview, "the Poet and the Poem" by Grace Cavalieri
  - Poet Lore vol. 110 no. 3/4, 2015; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    Includes Cavalieri introduction essay on Abdul Ali.
  - Poet Trees poetry hiding in plain sight, 2019; Series 4 (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - Poetry in the Air, 2008 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Poetry of Northwest Vol 8 No. 1, 1967; Series 4 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Poetry Today: A Quarterly Publication of the International Society of Poets, 2007 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    This issue includes Grace Cavalieri's advice on publishing article titled "Ask the Poet Advisor"
  - Poets and Artists, Issue no. 72, 2016; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 7)
    Includes Cavalieri poem "Portrait of the Basement Stairs".
  - Poets and Artists, Issue no.77, 2016 November; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 8)
    Includes Cavalieri poem "What The Psychic Said".
  - Poets and Artists, Issue no. 80, 2017 January; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 9)
    Includes Cavalieri poems "Hollow", "In Praise Of Oasis".
  - Poetry Quarterly, 2008 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Potomac Review issue 34, 2002-2003 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    This issue includes introduction of writing contest winners. Grace Cavalieri was a judge.
  - Prize poems of the National Federation of State Poetry Societies, 1965-1966-1967, 1968 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Way Well the Way a Poem Begins"
  - Psychological Perspectives vol. 2 no. 1, 1971 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Yesterday Dissolves"
  - The Raven Chronicles vol. 3 no. 2, 1993-1994 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "From Babies"
  - Redactions: Poetry and Poetics issue 12, Series 4 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    This issue includes the poem by Grace Cavalieri "Travelogue"
  - Review: "Breathing Rice", undated (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Review of "Chrysalides", 2010; Series 4 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    Grace's comments are on the back of the book.
  - Review of "Dulce Menendez", undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Review of "Kathy and Helen", undated (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Review of "Legacy", undated (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Review of "Signs and Symptoms", undated (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Review of "Renovation", undated (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Review of "Seasons of Flowers and Dust", undated (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - Review of "Taking the Road Where It Leads", undated (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Review of "Tired and Going Home", undated (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - Review "When I Said Goodbye", undated (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - The Rufus vol. 2 issue 2, 1974-1975 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "The Blouse" and "When Escaping From a Mental Hospital Don't Ask the Doctor to Make House Calls"
  - The Santa Fe Sun vol. 7 no. 3, 01/1995 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Tarot Card IX. Temperance"
  - The Santa Fe Sun New Mexico's Alternative Newspaper vol. 7 no. 2, 12/1994 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Bluebird of Happiness"
  - Salt Lick no. 5, 04/1970 (Box 81, Folder 15)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "With Fish"
  - SCAF Poets of 1968 (Box 81, Folder 16)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Black in Virginia"
  - Sheperdstown Theater Festival Article, 07/2008 (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - The Sligo Journal of Arts and Letters, Fall 2015/Spring 2016; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 15)
    Includes Cavalieri poems "Abeyance", "Tripe".
  - The Small Pond Magazine of literature Vol. 26 No. 3, 1989; Series 4 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Small Victories Review, undated (Box 88, Folder 17)
  - The Smith 11 Declaration of Independence, 1970; Series 4 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Sojourner: The Women's Forum vol. 15 no. 4, 12/1989 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Grandmother"
  - Solitary Singers: An Anthology of New Poets, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 18)
  - Solo Cafe 8 & 9, Vol. 2: Teachers & Students, 2012; Series 4 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Solo Nova V. 2, 2012; Series 4 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Song: "Who Will Occupy This Poem", 2009 (Box 88, Folder 19)
  - Sunday Gazette- mail, 01/17/1993 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "A Letter for the Inauguration of Gaston Caperton"
  - "Tell Me Where to Be Born" Foreword, undated (Box 88, Folder 20)
  - Texture Vol. 1, Issue 1, 2017; Series 4 (Box 116, Folder 7)
  - The American Poetry, 06/2008 (Box 88, Folder 21)
  - The American Poetry Review, 04/1997 (Box 88, Folder 22)
  - This I accomplish: Harriet Powers' Bible Quilt and other pieces, 2009; Series 4 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    Grace Cavalieri's play "Quilting the Sun" is mentioned.
  - Tigertail, A South Florida Poetry Annual vol. 4, 2006 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Letter from West Virginia"
  - Traditions of West Virginia Folk Culture and Educational Awareness vol. 10, 2007 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Walking the Property"
  - Upstreet no. 2, 2006 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Petty's Drugstore"
  - Uptown Beat vol. 3 no. 2, 1970 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "There is a Farm", "Entreat", "Daniel Berrigan" and "George Seferis"
  - Uptown Beat vol. 3 no. 3, 1970 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Captivity" and "Kneebends"
  - The View From Here, 2012; Series 4 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Voices International vol. 7 no. 1, 1972 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems "Ropes" and "Explosion in Mid-Air"
  - The Washington Book Review vol. 1 no. 4, 04/1986 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Easter Sunday"
  - The Washington Book Review vol. 1 no. 5, 05/1986 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Markings"
  - The Washington Dossier, 09/1982 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Social Elite"
  - Washington Post Book World, 04/2009 (Box 88, Folder 23)
  - Washington Review of the Arts vol. 2 no. 2, 1976 (Box 82, Folder 10)
    This issue includes a review by Grace Cavalieri's of the book A Niggered Amen by Ahmos Zu-Bolton II
  - Washington Review of the Arts vol. 2 no. 4, 1976-1977 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "The Apropos Mot"
  - Washington Review vol.26 no.6 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - West Virginia Magazine (arts and lettres) vol.2 no.5 (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - Whose Woods These Are, 1983 (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - White Roses, 07/2008 (Box 88, Folder 24)
  - Window poetry Washington DC #3, 1976; Series 4 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Woman Sphere vol. 1 no. 2, 09/1975 (Box 82, Folder 15)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Why I Cannot Take a Lover Part 3"
  - Word Wrights no. 14, 1998 (Box 82, Folder 16)
    Word Wrights
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poems, "Dementia, "Simple People Doing Simple Things" and "Unexpected Kind of Hope".
  - Writer's Digest, 04/2007 (Box 88, Folder 25)
  - Zone no. 1, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 17)
    This issue includes the Grace Cavalieri poem "Surprise Party"
  - Publications, 2010; Series 4 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    Folder title supplied by the donor for accession 2010.044
  - Publications, 1990-2013; Series 4 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    Includes anthologies of poems by various artists: "Into the Blue" and Poetry Center 1990 Anthology Passaic County Community College." Also has 2 reviews, one by Grace and one of her work.
  - Published works [1/2], 2008-2014; Series 4 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    Grace's reviews of Always the Trains by Judy Neri, Prodigal by Anne Caston.
  - Published works [2/2], 2208-2104; Series 4 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    Grace's review of Thieves in the Family by Maria Lisella.
  - Published works, 2012 August; Series 4 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    Poets and Artists: Issue #37 - August 2012. Includes Grace's poem entitled "Listen".
  - Published works, 2013 December; Series 4 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    Poets and Artists, Issue #51, December 2013. Includes Grace's poem entitled "The Circus".
  - Published works, 2013; Series 4 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    Includes loose poems "Beyond its Possibilities," "The Horses Before They Start," "Messages from the Other World," October 2013 Poetry Reviews for the Washington Independent Review of Books, A Tribute to Irene McKinney, "In the Meadow," "In Praise of Tiny Ants Without Sorrow," November 2013 Poetry Reviews
  - Published works [1/4], 2013; Series 4 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    The Baltimore Review 2013. Includes one poem entitled "The Portrait".
  - Published works [2/4], 2013-2014; Series 4 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    Poets and Artists Issue #48, September 2013. Includes Grace's poem "I'll take that as a compliment". Paterson Literary Review Issue #41, 2013-2014. Includes Grace's interview with Philip Levine.
  - Published works [3/4], 2013; Series 4 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    Grace's review of Shakespeare Theatre Company's production of "The Winter's Tale," "Messages from the Other World," September 2013 Poetry Reviews, October 2013 Poetry Reviews, June 2013 Poetry Reviews, July 2013 Poetry Reviews, Contemporary American Theater Festival 2013 Reviews, "Old Lady Sings the Blues" in MiPOesias the Blues Issue February 2013.
  - Published works [4/4], 2013; Series 4 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    Grace's reviews of the following poetry chapbooks: "Taken Away" by Carolyn Cecil, "Sound Effects" by Nina Bennett, "The Green Light" by Kathi Wolfe.
  - Published works [1/2], 2013-2014; Series 4 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    Lummox Number Two, 2013. Includes Grace's poem "At Home."
  - Published works [2/2], 2013-2014; Series 4 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    December, revival issue, Volume 24, Winter 2013. Includes Grace's poem "Beyond Its Possibilities", "The Horses Before They Start". impoesias, February 2014. Includes Grace's interview with Shara McCallum, Teri Cross Davis, Kenneth Carroll.
  - Published works [1/3], 2013-2014; Series 4 (Box 108, Folder 6)
    February 2014 Poetry Reviews; January 2014 Poetry Reviews; MiPOesias January 2014 with Grace interviewing Lisa Marie Basile, Shara McCullum, Teri Cross Davis; Grace's interview with Linda Lee Bukowski; Paterson Literary Review 2013 interview with Philip Levine; The Great Falls: An Anthology about Paterson, New Jersy "Dear Ken in an Orange Sweater"; miPOesias April 2014 interview with Vincent Katz; Poetry's Here @ Your Maryland Library "In the Pinecrest Rest Home"; "Gray's Tea Room, 1940" Allen Ginsberg Award 2013; miPOesias April 2014 interview with Brian Gilmore; danmurano.com "A Judge's Notebook" The 2013 Marfield Prize for Writing in the Arts; March 2014 Poetry Reviews; MiPOesias April 2014 interview with Yvette Neisser Moreno, MiPOesias April 2014 interview with Sharon Dolin; Lips Magazine 2014 p. 40 - 41 "One Year Ago Today".
  - Published works [2/3], 2013-2014; Series 4 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    December revival issue, Volume 24, Winter 2013. Includes Grace's poems "Beyond Its Possibilities" which was nominated for Pushcart Prize 2013, "The Horses Before They Start".
  - Published works [3/3], 2013-2014; Series 4 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    Grace's review of "Heart and Soul" by Carolyn Grassi.
  - Published works [1/4], 2014; Series 4 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    July 2014 Poetry Reviews, June 2014 Poetry Reviews, The Great Falls An Anthology about Paterson, New Jersey 2014 includes Grace's poem "Dear Ken in an Orange Sweater", impoesias June 2014 includes Grace's poems "A Brightening Note", "The Day They Gave Husbands Away", and an interview with Stacey Harwood and David Lehman.
  - Published works [2/4], 2014; Series 4 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    The Art of Survival -- An Anthology, includes Grace's poems "Grandmother", "Tarot Card VI. The Lovers", "Navy Wife", "HIV".
  - Published works [3/4], 2014; Series 4 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    Washington Independent Review of Books A Sampler, includes an article "Introduction to Poetry Reviews by Grace Cavalieri" by Joyce Shepperd, and Grace's October 2013 Exemplar Poetry Reviews.
  - Published works [4/4], 2014; Series 4 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    danmurano.com "A Judge's Notebook" on The 2013 Marfield Prize for Writing in the Arts, a print of Grace's untitled poem with art by Amy Nichols, The Loch Raven Review Summer 2013 including poems "Consumer's Report", "Fixation", Poets and Artists Magazine Issue #54, April 2014 including poems "Tide Flow Ebb", "The Peak", Paterson Literary Review "Gray's Tea Room, 1940" First Prize winner.
  - Published Works [1/3], 2014-February 2015; Series 4 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Published Works [2/3], 2014-February 2015; Series 4 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Published Works [3/3], 2014-February 2015; Series 4 (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Published Works, 2015 October; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 10)
  - Published Works, 2016 January; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 11)
  - Published Works, 2016 January-March; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 12)
  - Published Works, 2016 April-July; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 13)
  - Published Works, 2016 September-December; Series 4 (Box 113, Folder 14)
- Writings, Production, and Publicity, 1956-2019; Series 5
  Arrangement is alphabetical by title or subject, and maintains much of Cavalieri's original arrangement.
  This series consists of material related to the evolution of Grace Cavalieri's published and unpublished work from conception to production to promotion. The bulk of the material dates from 1968 to 2019, and includes both poetry and prose, such as plays, essays, articles, interviews, and radio and television scripts. Included in this series are notes and notebooks; research materials; drafts; translations; mock-ups, galleys, and page proofs for published works. The notes and notebooks range from complete poems and project proposals, to fragmentary jottings and lists. Research materials include correspondence and copies of scholarly articles. The series also includes material related to the production of Cavalieri's plays, such as cast lists, scripts, budgets, correspondence, and photographs. Promotional material for Cavalieri's writing includes flyers, posters, brochures, programs, press releases, postcards, clippings, and reviews. Material related to events and readings surrounding Cavalieri's writing is also included, and this consists mainly of flyers and clippings. Material relevant to Cavalieri's professional life as a writer, such as biographical essays, bibliographies, curricula vitae, literary prizes and awards, and staging or reproduction permissions is also included.
  - One Act Plays Volume one [1/4], undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Plays include: "The Late and Blooming Early Branch", "We Regret to Inform You That The Destiny Of Future Generations Is Uncertain Because of a General Inability On The Part Of All Night Watchmen", "Birds That Call Before The Rain",
  - One Act Plays Volume one [2/4], undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Plays include: "The Death of a Child by Beating or not", "What Shall We Do Yesterday", "Heads", "The Planned Escape of Bonita and Bright"
  - One Act Plays Volume one [3/4], undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Plays include: "Old Favorites", Eleventh Hour Song", "Smarts (a play of the sixties", "Backyard Fun", "Cuffed Frays"
  - One Act Plays Volume one [4/4], undated (Box 25, Folder 5)